Finding Aid for Charles William Ungermann papers, 1915-1967
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Charles William Ungermann papers 1915-1967
Ungermann, Charles William, d. 1968.
1 linear foot and 2 oversize folders
88542 Aa 2; UAm; UAl
Detroit, Michigan, police officer. Scrapbooks containing material concerning the Detroit Police Department and Ungermann's career; also photographs.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of the Charles Ungermann family (donor no. 5613 ).
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Charles W. Ungermann was a long-time member of the Detroit Police Department. He died in 1968.
The collection consists of scrapbooks relating to his career, to the activities of the police department, and to civil defense activities. The photographs in the collection are of Detroit, Michigan buildings, streets, people, and activities, especially as they relate to the work of the Detroit Police Department; group and individual portraits and photographs of Detroit Police, and photos of police training; photos of war bond drives and other war work during World War II; and photos of WJR radio broadcasting during the 1930s.
Subjects:
Detroit (Mich.). Police Dept.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Airships.; American Legion.; Automobile industry.; Automobiles.; Baseball.; Belle Isle Bridge (Detroit, Mich.); Broadcasting--1931-1940.; Buildings--Michigan--Detroit.; Buses.; Business enterprises--Michigan--Detroit.; Children.; City and town life.; Community service.; Detroit (Mich.); Detroit (Mich.)--Buildings.; Detroit (Mich.)--Business enterprises.; Detroit (Mich.)--Fires.; Detroit (Mich.)--Police stations.; Detroit (Mich.)--Streets.; Detroit (Mich.). Police Dept.; Detroit Tigers (Baseball team); Fires--Michigan--Detroit.; General Motors Corporation.; Ice skating.; Knights Templar (Masonic order); Minstrel shows.; Orchard Lake (Mich.); Parades and processions.; Picnics.; Police--Michigan--Detroit.; Police stations--Michigan--Detroit.; Ste. Claire (Ship); Shrine of the Little Flower (Royal Oak, Mich.); Streets--Michigan--Detroit.; Traffic accidents.; Ungermann, Charles William, d. 1968.; WJR (Radio station: Detroit, Mich.); War bonds and funds.; War work.; World War, 1939-1945.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Scrapbooks.
- Scrapbooks
  - Personal (Box 1)
    (includes photographs)
  - Police (Box 1)
  - Civil defense (Box 1)
- Photographs
  - Airships at Ford Airport (Box 1)
  - American Legion parade, 1931 (Box 1)
  - Automobile accidents (Box 1)
  - Automobile industry (Box 1)
  - Detroit and vicinity views: includes burning of Belle Isle Bridge, 1915, and Shrine of the Little Flower (Box 1)
    (see also oversize folder UAm)
  - Detroit police (Box 1)
  - Fisher Body Craftsmants Guild: includes General Motors Buildings and Bob-Lo boat (St. Claire) (Box 1)
  - Knights Templar parade, 1928 (Box 1)
  - WJR radio broadcasts (Box 1)
  - World Series, 1935 (Box 1)
  - Detroit Art Center, 1920s (Folder UAl)
    (in oversize folder UAl)